

## **Profile**

An experienced and talented technical writer, I create task-based documentation tailored for target audiences - the right documentation, at the right time, via the right channel.

I am passionate about user experience, content strategy, and open standards such as DITA. I am interested in exploring the ways Agile methodologies and cloud-based infrastructure can improve content development and hosting.

CORE EXPERTISE

Research & Analysis • Strategic Planning • Project & Program Management • Information/Content Architecture • Quality Assurance

# Experience

INFOR - ST PAUL, MN

TECHNICAL PROGRAM MANAGER - 06/2021-10/2022

Coordinated, tracked, and reported on strategic projects for the global information development (infodev) department, including a portfolio of six products in addition to other initiatives

Coached 14 full- and part-time infodev architects on topics such Agile methods, product road maps, and technical training opportunities

Originated and coordinated the process for infodev internal project work intake, work prioritization, and capacity planning; as a result, the architects completed more than a dozen strategic initiatives in less than 15 months

Collaborated with other departments on projects such as implementation of a search service on the documentation website (full-text search of over 1 million html topics), ongoing development and rollout of the embedded user-assistance app, definition of documentation versioning practices and standards

Facilitated the ongoing architecture, maintenance, and delivery of the documentation website, fulfilling several roles such as quality analyst, developer, and release manager for bimonthly major, minor, or patch releases

Acted as department liaison and subject-matter expert for AWS architecture, accounts, and services, and Infor DevOps tools and processes

### PRINCIPAL INFORMATION DEVELOPER - 09/2013-06/2021

Designed and developed a hosted model for docs, including a front end, admin console, and API as microservices; the website launched on AWS in January 2018, grew to 2 million html topics by September 2022, and supports millions of hits per day

Developed the proof of concept, then managed the project to build an API-based embedded user assistance app, which was adopted by over 20 products by 2022

Implemented and supported DITA-based CCMS with over 100 global users

Devised and instituted a content strategy for product doc, as well as information architecture and design of online help

Charity Fretty charityfretty@gmail.com

Designed and wrote administrator and end user product documentation for Java-based technology platform

HEALTHLAND - MINNEAPOLIS, MN

**TECHNICAL WRITER - 10/2011-09/2013** 

Authored and updated documentation for healthcare software solutions and third-party products, including installation and configuration instructions, reference guides, and online help for internal and external audiences

Created release materials and client communications for product releases, which entailed one large release and quarterly and monthly patches

Participated in the administration, QA testing, maintenance, and design of the client portal and LMS, including the development and design of a knowledge base

Organized and led a client focus group to solicit feedback on end user deliverables and to gain insight on client portal adoption

LAWSON SOFTWARE - ST PAUL, MN

LEAD INFORMATION DEVELOPER - 12/2008-10/2011

Planned, wrote, and edited user, administration, and reference documentation for healthcare and public sector industries

Assisted in the design and roll out of new documentation presentations, including Eclipse Infocenters for online help systems

Identified and lead strategic information development infrastructure initiatives and worked with senior management to determine priorities, costs, and resourcing of projects

Collaborated in the design, testing, roll out, and training of customizations to CMS and XML authoring tools

Implemented issue tracking software for the operations team

# Early Career

MANAGER, INFORMATION DEVELOPMENT, LAWSON SOFTWARE 06/2005-12/2008 INFORMATION DEVELOPER, LAWSON SOFTWARE 03/2001-06/2005 CONSULTANT, INFORMATION DESIGN SERVICES, SPHERION 12/1998-03/2001 TECHNICAL WRITER, CIPRICO 01/1997-12/1998

### Education

Minnesota State University, Moorhead – B.A. English and Mass Communications, 1996

#### Skills

- CCMS (IXIASOFT CCMS)
- XML authoring tools (Oxygen, XMetaL, Arbortext)
- HTML
- Read, understand, and write simple code: json, JavaScript, yaml, regex, java, sql
- Wiki (Confluence)
- Issue tracking and project management (Jira, Roadmunk)
- Cloud-hosted applications and services (AWS, containerization, microservice architecture)

Charity Fretty charityfretty@gmail.com

• Adobe Technical Communications Suite (Acrobat Pro, FrameMaker, RoboHelp)

- MS Office Suite and flowcharts and diagramming tools (Lucidchart, Visio)
- Source code management (git, GitLab)